forestessentialsindia.com 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy

\- Date of Effect

\- Information We Collect

\- How We Use Your Personally Identifiable Information

\- Technologies that Allow Us to Customise Your Experience on Forest Essentials Online

\- Information We Share and Who We Share With

\- How We Protect Personal Information

\- Updates to Our Privacy Policy

\- Comments

\- Concerning Facebook

**DATE OF EFFECT:**

This Privacy Policy comes into effect from Oct 1 2010

Thank you for visiting Forest Essentials’ Online Store which is currently located at www.forestessentialsindia.com . Your visit to this website is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions.

We at Forest Essentials Online are committed to protecting and safeguarding your privacy.

This Privacy Policy describes the types of personal information we collect on the Forest Essentials website, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Policy also describes the measures we take to protect the security of this information as well as how you can access, modify or delete your personal information at any time. It also explains how you can object to the processing of your personal information or to receiving communications about our products and services.

This Privacy Policy governs only information provided to Forest Essentials Online. It does not govern any other information or communications that may have been collected through Forest Essentials' brick and mortar retail stores or collected in any other manner like promotions, personal contact programmes, etc.

By accepting the Privacy Policy, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Information We Collect**

In general, you can visit the Forest Essentials Online without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information. You can however, also register at our website which enables us to contact you by email or text messages on your mobile phone to inform you about our products or respond to your comments or queries. As part of the registration process, we collect and store your personal information that you may choose to provide us with, such as your name, email address, mobile phone number and date of birth.

The technology that we use also allows us to collect aggregate information that does not identify you personally but lets us know your technology usage like the Uniform Resource Locater, Internet Protocol address, your operating system and browser type, etc. We may collect, compile, store, publish, promote, report, or otherwise disclose or use any such aggregate information which does not personally identify you. If any such aggregate information is correlated to you, it will be protected like any other personally identifiable information as described under this Privacy Policy.  
Credit Card , Debit Card and Banking Information

Forest Essentials Online does not collect or store Credit Card or Debit Card or banking information. Such information may be provided by you during the purchase transaction. However this data does not come to Forest Essentials Online. It is directly transmitted through the payment gateway provider to the payment network or bank . No information is stored by Forest Essentials Online

_Data Hosting_

The website is hosted with third party data hosting specialists. Information collected is kept on servers owned and managed by data hosting companies, which may be in India or overseas including the United States of America. The companies being used by Forest Essentials Online are PCI compliant and have data security processes in place. However Forest Essentials is not liable for any data theft or breach of security at the data centres hosting the website and holding consumer data

**How We Use Your Personally Identifiable Information**

_Marketing Emails_

The information you have chosen to provide may be used by Forest Essentials Online to create and deliver to you emails such as our newsletters, surveys or other email messages containing product and event information, cosmetics tips or promotions. If at any time you decide that you would not like to receive these emails, you may select the ‘Unsubscribe’ link on the email or edit your information and consent to receive email and other communication in the ‘Profile’ section for registered users

_Text Messages_

If you have chosen to leave your mobile phone number on Forest Essentials Online, you may receive text message/SMS alerts containing product and event information, cosmetics tips or promotions on your mobile phone. Please note that Forest Essentials Online will never send you any unsolicited text message on your mobile phone. Forest Essentials Online does not charge any fee for you to receive any text message from us. However, your mobile service provider may charge you for sending and/or receiving text messages and air-time, as well as any other standard applicable rates charged by your mobile service provider.

_Telephone calls_

If you have chosen to leave your mobile phone number or landline number on Forest Essentials Online, you may receive phone calls containing product and event information, cosmetics tips or promotions on your mobile phone or landline phone.

_Communications to Serve You_

If you have chosen to provide us with your contact information, we may provide you with service related announcements by any means, including email, concerning the website or contact you regarding your customer service requests or questions. For example, all registered users will receive a welcoming email to confirm their registration. These types of communications are necessary to serve you, respond to your concerns and to provide the high level of customer service that Forest Essentials Online offers its customers.

_Customised Service_

We may use your personal information you have chosen to give us to provide you with customised service and use of our website. For example, we may suggest products that would be of particular interest to you. Such customised information may be conveyed to you by way of emails or text messages/sms and phone calls

_Special Events, Questionnaires and Surveys_

On occasion, Forest Essentials Online may sponsor special events (such as contests, promotions or other offerings), questionnaires and surveys. There may be specific rules applicable to these promotions that explain how any personal information you provide will be processed. We strongly suggest you review any applicable rules before participating. To the extent any special event, questionnaire or survey is not subject to specific rules, the processing of personal information is governed by this Privacy Policy and the purposes it sets forth.

_Employment_

If you provide personal information to us with respect to employment, such as your resume, we will treat such personal information as confidential and use it only to consider you for current and future employment opportunities and to contact you with respect to employment with us or our affiliates. An "Affiliate" is a person or entity that directly or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls or is controlled by, or is under common control with, our company. We will retain your information for further recruitment opportunities that may arise, unless you tell us that you no longer wish for us to retain your information.

**Technologies that Allow Us to Customise Your Experience on Forest Essentials Online**

We use various technologies to collect information relating to your visit to our website, such as the Uniform Resource Locater (URL) that referred you to our website, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, etc. This enables us to enhance and customise your experience on our website. For example, we may collect the Internet Protocol (IP) address identifying your computer or device and indicating your geographic region for statistical purposes. In some instances, we may use these technologies in combination with the personally identifiable information you provide on the website. These technologies may provide a variety of information such as whether you have visited Forest Essentials Online before. They also may enable you to save your preferences. Each technology is explained below.

_Web Beacons and Tracking Links_

Web Beacons (also called clear gifs and pixel tags), tracking links and/or similar technology consist of a few lines of code and are embedded on the pages of our website. They are often used in combination with Cookies and are often not visible to the user of the website. Web Beacons may relay information to third parties such as our service providers and may be used in order to track customer response to certain advertising, to better target interactive advertising and to enhance customer support and usability. If you reject our Cookies (see Cookie section below), you will prevent Web Beacons from relaying this information about you and may limit your use of some of our website features.

_Cookies_

Browser Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our website. Flash Cookies are similar to Browser Cookies except that they can store data more complex than simple text and are stored in your browser rather than on your hard drive. You can have your browser and/or plugs to your browser, such as flash, notify you of, or automatically reject, Cookies. If you reject our Cookies or opt-out of the use of cookies, you may still use this website, but you may be limited in the use of some of its features.

**Information We Share and Who We Share With**

We will not provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for their use in marketing their products or services to you without your consent, except as provided in the “Business Transfers” Section below. In addition, we do not sell or otherwise disclose personally identifiable information about our website visitors except as described here.

_Forest Essentials Affiliates_

We may share your personal information with our Affiliates that distribute and market Forest Essentials products. Our Affiliates may use this information in accordance with this Privacy Policy including, if you have so chosen, sending you product information, cosmetic tips or promotions. If you prefer that we not share your personal information with our Affiliates, please do not provide it to us. We are unable to offer the benefits of Forest Essentials Online to anyone who does not consent to the sharing of their personal information with our Affiliates.

_Third Parties_

We may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf consistent with this Privacy Policy. Examples include webstore management companies, order processing companies, courier companies, data analysis firms, customer support specialists, email vendors, web-hosting companies and fulfilment companies (e.g., companies that coordinate mailings). Such third parties may be provided with access to personal information needed to perform their functions but may not use such information other than on our behalf and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

In addition, in some instances, you may be offered the opportunity to consent to the sharing of your information with a third party such as an event or promotion co-sponsor. If you consent, we will share your information with such third party and the information you provide may be used by such third party for their own purposes and in accordance with their own policies.

_Business Transfers_

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell certain of our assets. In such transactions, user information, including personal information, generally is one of the transferred business assets, and by submitting your personally identifiable information on the website you agree that your data may be transferred to such parties in these circumstances.

_Compliance With Law_

We may disclose information that is necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request. In addition, we may disclose any information when it is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with suspected or actual illegal activity.

_Transfer of Data to Other Countries_

Forest Essentials, our Affiliates and third parties who may receive your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the databases in which your personal information is stored shall be located in India and are required to honour the privacy representations made in this Privacy Policy under applicable laws of this country. In case of transfer of data to any other country, legal protections applicable to personal information in the concerned country will apply.

_Children's Privacy_

The Forest Essentials Online website is not designed for persons under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years of age, you may browse Forest Essentials Online, but please do not provide your personal information to us. For example, you cannot register. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of 13 on the website, we will delete the information from our records.

**How We Protect Personal Information**

We maintain reasonable safeguards for this website to protect against unauthorised disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of the personal information you provide on Forest Essentials Online. If you have any questions about security at our Site, you can email us at [legal@forestessentialsindia.com](mailto:legal@forestessentialsindia.com)

**Updates to Our Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised policy here. We suggest that you periodically consult this Privacy Policy. Please find the effective date of the Privacy Policy at the top of this page.

We have taken great efforts to ensure that your visit to Forest Essentials Online is an excellent and fruitful one and that your privacy is constantly respected. If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us by email at [legal@forestessentialsindia.com](mailto:legal@forestessentialsindia.com)

Worldwide Copyright © Mountain Valley Springs India Pvt Ltd. (brand owners of Forest Essentials). All worldwide rights reserved.

**CONCERNING FACEBOOK**

On our pages, you will find a button linking to our Facebook page. Please note that, with the use of this button, data about the visit to our pages can be linked to your Facebook profile.

If you do not wish to transmit data to Facebook, please ensure that you are logged out of Facebook while entering our pages.

Please also be sure to note the data protection notices of Facebook if you wish to use the corresponding button on our pages. The information about data protection at Facebook can be found at: <http://wwww.facebook.com/about/privacy>
